[
    {
        "Question":"50 year old man complains of recent onset diplopia. On examination he is unable to look inward and downwards with his right eye; the most Likely diagnosis is a lesion of the:",
        "Option 1":"Abducens nerve",
        "Option 2":"Ciliary ganglion",
        "Option 3":"Nasociliary nerve",
        "Option 4":"Oculomotor nerve",
        "Option 5":"Trochlear nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Trochlear nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a patient developed extradural hematoma following a RTA , on examination, he was found to have diplopia on abducted eye, what nerve is most likely affected?",
        "Option 1":"Abducens",
        "Option 2":"Oculomotor",
        "Option 3":"Optic",
        "Option 4":"Facial",
        "Option 5":"Trochlear",
        "Correct Answer":"Abducens"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 32 year old man , cook by profession, presented with history of road traffic accident and had signs and symptoms of increased intracranial pressure. He was found to have dilatation of the pupil on the side of the injury. What is the likely reason for his pupillary dilatation?",
        "Option 1":"Optic nerve injury",
        "Option 2":"Overaction of parasympathetic stimulation",
        "Option 3":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 4":"Lack of sympathetic",
        "Option 5":"Unopposed sympathetic stimulation",
        "Correct Answer":"Unopposed sympathetic stimulation"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50-year-old woman attends her general practitioner due to change in appearance. She finds difficulty removing her rings, reports: an increase in shoe size and photographs reveal a change in her facial appearance. Visual field tests are performed to direct confrontation. Which of the following defects is most likely to be associated with her presentation?",
        "Option 1":"Binasal hemianopia",
        "Option 2":"Bitemporal hemianopia",
        "Option 3":"Right homogenous hemianopia",
        "Option 4":"Unilateral loss of vision",
        "Option 5":"Left homogenous hemianopia",
        "Correct Answer":"Bitemporal hemianopia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50 year old man complains of recent onset diplopia. On examination, he is unable to look inward and downwards with his right eye; the most likely diagnosis is a lesion of the ?",
        "Option 1":"Superior rectus muscle",
        "Option 2":"Inferior rectus muscle",
        "Option 3":"Superior oblique",
        "Option 4":"Inferior oblique",
        "Option 5":"Lateral rectus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior oblique"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 56 year old man presents with headache and vomiting with deterioration over the last two weeks. On examination, he has papilledema. A CT scan shows a space occupying lesion in the right parietal lobe. He develops a sudden homonymous hemianopia. Which part of the visual system to be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Lens",
        "Option 2":"Optic chiasm",
        "Option 3":"Optic radiation",
        "Option 4":"Retina",
        "Option 5":"Second cranial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Optic radiation"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32 year old man, cook by profession, presented with history of RTA and had signs and symptoms of increased intracranial pressure. He was found to have dilatation of the pupil on the side of the injury. Which nerve is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Parasympathetic carried on the oculomotor",
        "Option 2":"Sympathetic damage carried on the arteries",
        "Option 3":"Trochlear nerve",
        "Option 4":"Abducent nerve",
        "Option 5":"Optic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Parasympathetic carried on the oculomotor"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 44 year old female complained from her visual disturbance and eye opacity, by examination, she lost her pupillary light reflex and accommodation, which cranial nerves in light reflex damaged?",
        "Option 1":"1 and 5",
        "Option 2":"2 and 3",
        "Option 3":"10 and 9",
        "Option 4":"1 and 3",
        "Option 5":"3 and 7",
        "Correct Answer":"2 and 3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Within the posterior triangle, which nerve is at risk of damage during surgery?",
        "Option 1":"Auricular branch of the facial",
        "Option 2":"Glossopharnyngeal",
        "Option 3":"Phrenic",
        "Option 4":"Recurrent laryngeal",
        "Option 5":"Spinal accessory",
        "Correct Answer":"Spinal accessory"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35 year old man is admitted to hospital with vomiting, nausea and severe headaches. An MRI scan reveals a tumor of the cerebellopontine angle which one of the following pairs of cranial nerves is most likely to be compressed by this tumor?",
        "Option 1":"Accessory and vagus",
        "Option 2":"Facial and vagus",
        "Option 3":"Facial and vestibulocochlear",
        "Option 4":"Glossopharyngeal and vestibulocochlear",
        "Option 5":"Vagus and vestibulocochlear",
        "Correct Answer":"Facial and vestibulocochlear"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with a central nervous system tumor causing paralysis of the glossopharyngeal and vagus nerves and absent gag reflex. What is the most likely location of the tumor?",
        "Option 1":"Mid-brain",
        "Option 2":"Pons",
        "Option 3":"Medulla",
        "Option 4":"Ventricles",
        "Option 5":"Cervical cord",
        "Correct Answer":"Medulla"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 16 year old boy is hit on the left side of the face by a ball. There are no broken bones, but the  boy complains of numbness of the face below the eye. Which nerve has most likely been compromised?",
        "Option 1":"Abducens nerve",
        "Option 2":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Infraorbital nerve",
        "Option 5":"Zygomatic",
        "Correct Answer":"Infraorbital nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Post parotidectomy patient developed gustatory sweating during meals, what is the mechanism?",
        "Option 1":"Regeneration of the parasympathetic fibers of the auriculotemporal nerve into sympathetic fibers innervating the sweat gland",
        "Option 2":"Regeneration of the sympathetic fibers on the parasympathetic of auriculotemporal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Regeneration of facial nerve after its injury",
        "Option 4":"Regeneration of great auricular nerve on sympathetic fibers innervating the sweat gland",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Regeneration of the parasympathetic fibers of the auriculotemporal nerve into sympathetic fibers innervating the sweat gland"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Facial nerve transection (Bell\u2019s palsy) after parotidectomy surgery will lead to all except:",
        "Option 1":"Numbness over the cheek",
        "Option 2":"Loss of corneal reflex",
        "Option 3":"Lower lip drooping",
        "Option 4":"Drop of angle of mouth",
        "Option 5":"Inability to raise the eyebrow",
        "Correct Answer":"Numbness over the cheek"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After extradural hemorrhage surgery , the patient complains of lateral squint, ptosis, which nerve is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Optic nerve",
        "Option 2":"Oculomotor nerve",
        "Option 3":"Trochlear nerve",
        "Option 4":"Abducens nerve",
        "Option 5":"Trigeminal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Oculomotor nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"43 year old man presented with recent onset right eye diplopia. When she looks towards left, whis is what happens. Which cranial nerve is affected?",
        "Option 1":"trochlear",
        "Option 2":"oculomotor",
        "Option 3":"abducens",
        "Option 4":"optic tract",
        "Option 5":"vagus",
        "Correct Answer":"trochlear"
    },
    {
        "Question":"10 year old child presents with progressive facial weakness and squint. On examination, there is lower motot neuron facial weakness and failure of abduction of one eye. An MRI scan shows a small intrinsic mass lesion within the central nervous system. Where is this most likely to be located?",
        "Option 1":"The cerebellar vermis",
        "Option 2":"The medulla",
        "Option 3":"The midbrain",
        "Option 4":"The pons",
        "Option 5":"Spinal cord",
        "Correct Answer":"The pons"
    },
    {
        "Question":"32 year old man presents with a painful torticollis there is no past medical history and his only complaint is that he has been feeling rather tired over the last 4 nights. On examination, he has large rubbery mass in the lateral aspect of his neck as well as a few smaller masses along his internal jugular vein. You correctly assume that the mascular neck spasm and the large mass are connected. The most likely cause of his torticollis is due to pressure on?",
        "Option 1":"Ansa cervicalis",
        "Option 2":"Cervical plexus branch",
        "Option 3":"Cranial accessory nerve",
        "Option 4":"Spinal accessory nerve",
        "Option 5":"Vagus",
        "Correct Answer":"Spinal accessory nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"35 year old man develops lower lip numbness after tooth extraction. What is the nerve affected?",
        "Option 1":"Lingual nerve",
        "Option 2":"Inferior alveolar nerve",
        "Option 3":"Marginal mandibular branch of facial nerve",
        "Option 4":"facial nerve",
        "Option 5":"hypoglossal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior alveolar nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 19 year old man was assaulted and sustained injuries to the right side of his head. After two weeks he notices his right eye is dry and it could not produce tears. From which ganglion is post synaptic fibers arise to supply the lacrimal gland?",
        "Option 1":"Geniculate ganglion",
        "Option 2":"Inferior ganglion of the vagus nerve",
        "Option 3":"Otic ganglion",
        "Option 4":"Pterygopalatine ganglion",
        "Option 5":"Superior cervical ganglion",
        "Correct Answer":"Pterygopalatine ganglion"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 42 years old man experienced by loss of tasted sensation from anterior 2\/3 rd of the tongue. Which ganglion is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Gasserian",
        "Option 2":"Otic",
        "Option 3":"Geniculate",
        "Option 4":"Pterygopalatine",
        "Option 5":"Submandibular",
        "Correct Answer":"Geniculate"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 19 year old man was assaulted and sustained injuries to the right side of the head. After two weeks he notices his right eye is dry and it could not produce tears. Which nucleus is affected in the brain?",
        "Option 1":"Superior saltatory nucleus",
        "Option 2":"Inferior saltatory nucleus",
        "Option 3":"Edinger wistiphal nucleus",
        "Option 4":"Ambiguous nucleus",
        "Option 5":"Dorsal vagal nucleus",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior saltatory nucleus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A man suffers a brachial plexus injury. On examination he has a horner\u2019s syndrome in association with upper limb paralysis. Which nerve roots does the horner\u2019s syndrome suggest involvement of?",
        "Option 1":"C2 \u2013 3",
        "Option 2":"C4-5",
        "Option 3":"C6-7",
        "Option 4":"C8-T1",
        "Option 5":"T2-3",
        "Correct Answer":"C8-T1"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A man suffers a pancost tumor. On examination, he has a horner\u2019s syndrome in association with upper limb paralysis. Which nerve roots does the horner syndrome suggest involvement of ?",
        "Option 1":"C6",
        "Option 2":"C7",
        "Option 3":"C8",
        "Option 4":"T1",
        "Option 5":"T2",
        "Correct Answer":"T1"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50 year old man undergoes surgery for a large left sided carotid body tumor. Post operative his left pupils are smaller than right and his left eye lid drops. This is due to :",
        "Option 1":"A central embolus affecting the third cranial nerve nucleus",
        "Option 2":"Damage to cervical sympathetic chain on the left side",
        "Option 3":"Damage to the left vagus",
        "Option 4":"Damage to the left facial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Hypotension due to surgery leads to ischemia of ciliary ganglion",
        "Correct Answer":"Damage to cervical sympathetic chain on the left side"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 25 year old woman undergoes an elective right thoracoscopic procedure for treatment of right palmer hyperhidrosis. Diathermy is applied to a neural structure lying anterior to the neck of tire right first rib. What is the most likely complication to occur as a result of this procedure?",
        "Option 1":"Bradycardia",
        "Option 2":"Hoarseness",
        "Option 3":"Horner\u2019s syndrome",
        "Option 4":"Raised right hemi diaphragm",
        "Option 5":"Reduced right biceps tendon reflex",
        "Correct Answer":"Horner\u2019s syndrome"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35 year old motorcyclist is involved in RTA and fractures his temporal bone, completely transecting the facial nerve just distal to the geniculate ganglion, which function of this nerve remains?",
        "Option 1":"Lacrimation",
        "Option 2":"Salivation from the submandibular gland",
        "Option 3":"Sensation to the anterior tongue",
        "Option 4":"Smile",
        "Option 5":"Taste",
        "Correct Answer":"Lacrimation"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which cranial nerve doesn\u2019t carry parasympathetic innervation?",
        "Option 1":"Facial",
        "Option 2":"Glossopharyngeal",
        "Option 3":"Trigeminal",
        "Option 4":"Vagus",
        "Option 5":"Oculomotor",
        "Correct Answer":"Trigeminal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After submandibular salivary gland surgery , salivation is impaired due to injury of which ganglion?",
        "Option 1":"Pterygopalatine",
        "Option 2":"Submandibular",
        "Option 3":"Gasserian",
        "Option 4":"Ciliary",
        "Option 5":"Stellate",
        "Correct Answer":"Submandibular"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with a central nervous system tumor causing paralysis of the glossopharyngeal and vagus nerves. What is the most likely location of the tumor?",
        "Option 1":"Mid-brain",
        "Option 2":"Pons",
        "Option 3":"Medulla",
        "Option 4":"Ventricles",
        "Option 5":"Cervical cord",
        "Correct Answer":"Medulla"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with fracture of the face involving maxilla and numbness over the cheek, which of the following nerves is most likely to be involved?\nmental",
        "Option 1":"Infraorbital",
        "Option 2":"Superior alveolar",
        "Option 3":"Auriculotemporal",
        "Option 4":"Supratrochlear",
        "Option 5":"Infraorbital",
        "Correct Answer":null
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient presented with penetrating injury in the lower part of his neck, his primary survey revealed no major vascular injury and the patient was stable. He later was found to have hoarseness of voice. Injury to which nerve can cause hoarseness?",
        "Option 1":"Glossopharyngeal",
        "Option 2":"Hypoglossal",
        "Option 3":"Facial",
        "Option 4":"Vagus",
        "Option 5":"Accessory",
        "Correct Answer":"Vagus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"34 years old man with stab injury in neck posterior to the sternomastoid muscle. Which of these structures does not associate with a major vessel during its course and may be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Accessory",
        "Option 2":"Phrenic",
        "Option 3":"Vagus",
        "Option 4":"Upper division of brachial plexus",
        "Option 5":"Axillary",
        "Correct Answer":"Accessory"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following is considered part of general sensation of facial nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Area above the temporomandibular joint",
        "Option 2":"Angle of mandible",
        "Option 3":"External auditory meatus",
        "Option 4":"Posterior third of tongue",
        "Option 5":"Anterior two third of tongue",
        "Correct Answer":"External auditory meatus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 38 year old man presented with recurrent swelling under his mandible for last one month. Investigations revealed it to be calculus in the submandibular duct. He has been scheduled to removal of the calculus. Which nerve is likely to get damaged during this surgery?",
        "Option 1":"Lingual nerve",
        "Option 2":"Hypoglossal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 4":"Chorda tympani",
        "Option 5":"Great auricular nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Lingual nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 year old male with stab injury of neck above hyoid bone form one side to side. He then presented with right side deviation of the tongue. What is the most affected structure?",
        "Option 1":"Lingual nerve",
        "Option 2":"Right hypoglossal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Left geniglossus muscle injury",
        "Option 4":"Left hyoglossus muscle injury",
        "Option 5":"Left palatoglossus muscle injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Right hypoglossal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"GP doctor is consenting for removal of carotid body tumor, which complication should be discussed with patient before operation",
        "Option 1":"Affection of movement of the diaphragm",
        "Option 2":"Horner\u2019s syndrome",
        "Option 3":"Dysphagia",
        "Option 4":"Facial nerve injury through corda tympani",
        "Option 5":"Vocal cord paralysis",
        "Correct Answer":"Vocal cord paralysis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Tibetan man presented by pulsatile neck swelling moves right to left and not move up and down, what is your provisional diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Carotid body tumor",
        "Option 2":"Carotid aneurysm",
        "Option 3":"Brachial cyst",
        "Option 4":"Cystic hygroma",
        "Option 5":"Thyroid swelling",
        "Correct Answer":"Carotid body tumor"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Nerve supply to angle of mandible is",
        "Option 1":"Auriculotemporal",
        "Option 2":"Great auricular",
        "Option 3":"Lesser occipital marginal mandibular",
        "Option 4":"Auricular branch of vagus",
        "Option 5":"Great auricular",
        "Correct Answer":null
    },
    {
        "Question":"Sensory nerve supply to the area behind the ear is by which nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Great auricular",
        "Option 2":"Lesser occipital",
        "Option 3":"Occipital",
        "Option 4":"Trigeminal",
        "Option 5":"Auriculotemporal",
        "Correct Answer":"Lesser occipital"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Gag reflex is when you touch the palate; there is contraction of muscles of palate and uvula. Which cranial nerve carry afferent fibers from gag reflex?",
        "Option 1":"Facial",
        "Option 2":"Trigeminal",
        "Option 3":"Glossopharyngeal",
        "Option 4":"Vagus",
        "Option 5":"Hypoglossal",
        "Correct Answer":"Glossopharyngeal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with a central nervous system tumor causing dysarthria, palate flaccid and tongue deviated. What is the most likely location of the tumor?",
        "Option 1":"Mid-brain",
        "Option 2":"Pons",
        "Option 3":"Medulla",
        "Option 4":"Ventricles",
        "Option 5":"Cervical cord",
        "Correct Answer":"Medulla"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following structures is at risk during parotid surgery?",
        "Option 1":"External carotid artery",
        "Option 2":"Digastric muscle",
        "Option 3":"Lingual nerve",
        "Option 4":"Lingual artery",
        "Option 5":"Facial vein",
        "Correct Answer":"External carotid artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After thyroid surgery, the patient complained from hoarseness of voice, which nerve is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Superior laryngeal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Accessory nerve",
        "Option 5":"Phrenic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Post thyroidectomy, 50 year old patient becomes unable to cough or clear his throat, which nerve is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Recurrent laryngeal",
        "Option 2":"Superior laryngeal",
        "Option 3":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Accessory",
        "Option 5":"Phrenic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior laryngeal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Singer can\u2019t sing high pitched sounds now post thyroidectomy, what is the most accepted nerve to be damaged during operation?",
        "Option 1":"Recurrent laryngeal",
        "Option 2":"Superior laryngeal",
        "Option 3":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Accessory",
        "Option 5":"Phrenic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior laryngeal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 67-year-old man undergoes a carotid endarterectomy and seems to recover well following surgery, when he is reviewed on the ward post operatively, he complains that his voice is hoarse, what is the most likely cause?",
        "Option 1":"Damage to accessory nerve",
        "Option 2":"Damage to the cervical plexus",
        "Option 3":"damage to the glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 4":"damage to the hypoglossal nerve",
        "Option 5":"damage to the vagus",
        "Correct Answer":"damage to the vagus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"following a carotid end arterectomy, a man notices that he has a weakness of his tongue. Damage to which of the following nerves is the most likely for this process?",
        "Option 1":"Hypoglossal",
        "Option 2":"Accessory",
        "Option 3":"Ansa cervicalis",
        "Option 4":"Vagus",
        "Option 5":"Cervical plexus",
        "Correct Answer":"Hypoglossal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient with TIA, he underwent left carotid endarterectomy and immediately post procedure he developed dysarthria and tongue deviation to the left. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Another TIA",
        "Option 2":"Hypogloassal nerve neuropraxia",
        "Option 3":"Middle cerebral artery occlusion",
        "Option 4":"Anterior cerebral artery occlusion",
        "Option 5":"Lingual nerve injury",
        "Correct Answer":"Hypogloassal nerve neuropraxia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presents to the clinic following a surgical procedure. She complains that she is unable to shrug her shoulder. What is the nerve injury?",
        "Option 1":"Accessory nerve",
        "Option 2":"Cervical plexus",
        "Option 3":"Ansa cervicalis",
        "Option 4":"Long thoracic nerve",
        "Option 5":"Axiallary nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Accessory nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 23 year man after RTA there is airway affection and needed tracheostomy, which of the listed structures has the least chance to get injured in this procedure?",
        "Option 1":"Ascending pharyngeal artery",
        "Option 2":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Anterior jugular artery",
        "Option 4":"Thyroid isthmus",
        "Option 5":"Platysma",
        "Correct Answer":"Ascending pharyngeal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After excision of submandibular gland, deviation of tongue is noted, what is the injured nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Lingual nerve",
        "Option 2":"Marginal mandibular nerve",
        "Option 3":"Hypoglossal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Vagus",
        "Option 5":"Glossopharyngeal",
        "Correct Answer":"Hypoglossal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"General sensation to lateral tongue innervated by which nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Lingual nerve",
        "Option 2":"Chorda tympani",
        "Option 3":"Glossopharyngeal",
        "Option 4":"Vagus",
        "Option 5":"Hypoglossal",
        "Correct Answer":"Lingual nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After mandibular fracture, there is numbness of the lower lips, which cranial nerve is involved?",
        "Option 1":"Buccal",
        "Option 2":"Mental",
        "Option 3":"Superior alveolar",
        "Option 4":"Lingual",
        "Option 5":"Marginal mandibular",
        "Correct Answer":"Mental"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient diagnosed that he has a herpes zoster complaining of pain in the tip of the nose, what is from the following at the same dermatome of the tip of the nose?",
        "Option 1":"Ear pinna",
        "Option 2":"Angle of mouth",
        "Option 3":"Jaw angle",
        "Option 4":"Cornea",
        "Option 5":"Lobule of the ear",
        "Correct Answer":"Cornea"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Differentiation between the UMNL and LMNL facial nerve palsy by which of the following actions?",
        "Option 1":"inability to raise the eyebrow",
        "Option 2":"inability to squeeze eye or close it",
        "Option 3":"inability to blow the cheek",
        "Option 4":"inability to whistle",
        "Option 5":"loss of sensation of lower lip",
        "Correct Answer":"inability to raise the eyebrow"
    },
    {
        "Question":"70 year old male with supra-glottic cancer with referred otalgia, which nerve is responsible for this referred pain?",
        "Option 1":"Trigeminal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Auriculotemporal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 5":"Vagus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Vagus nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male patient 34 years old came to the ENT doctor suffering from hyperacusis. Which nerve its injury cause hyperacusis?",
        "Option 1":"Greater petrosal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Nerve to stapedius",
        "Option 3":"Auriculotemporal",
        "Option 4":"Chorda tympani",
        "Option 5":"Buccal branch of facial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Nerve to stapedius"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 year old man felt on work and was unconscious for several minutes. At emergency department, apart from headache, he is only complains from hyperacusis, which nerve is mostly injured?",
        "Option 1":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal",
        "Option 3":"Maxillary branch of trigeminal",
        "Option 4":"Ophthalmic branch of trigeminal",
        "Option 5":"Vestibulocochlear nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Facial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"40 years old man presented after injury to the angle of the mandible, there is de-arranged movement during biting. What is the responsible muscle?",
        "Option 1":"Medial pterygoid",
        "Option 2":"Lateral pterygoid",
        "Option 3":"Temporalis",
        "Option 4":"Buccinator",
        "Option 5":"Orbicularis oris",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial pterygoid"
    },
    {
        "Question":"10 days after colonic resection for neoplasia, 77 year old man developed a temperature of 37.5 C , his wound is healing well and there are no apparent causes of sepsis. Later that day, he complains of chest pain and becomes acutely distressed. Which nerve responsible in pain in inferior alveolar molar teeth?",
        "Option 1":"Maxillary",
        "Option 2":"Inferior alveolar",
        "Option 3":"Auriculotemporal",
        "Option 4":"Lingual",
        "Option 5":"Facial",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior alveolar"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 25 year old man develops unilateral paralysis of the muscles of facial expression following blunt trauma to his skull during rugby match. Taste from the anterior 2\/3 of the tongue is preserved and he is not suffering from hyperacusis. Where on the course of facial nerve most likely to be damaged?",
        "Option 1":"Internal auditory meatus",
        "Option 2":"Geniculate ganglion",
        "Option 3":"Middle ear",
        "Option 4":"Parotid gland",
        "Option 5":"Stylomastoid foramen",
        "Correct Answer":"Stylomastoid foramen"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Female child suffered from hyperhidrosis. Thoracoscopic sympathectomy is done but ganglion is injured in front of neck of 1st rib cause horner syndrome. Which of the following ganglion is the cause of horner syndrome?",
        "Option 1":"Gasserian ganglion",
        "Option 2":"Pterygopalatine ganglion",
        "Option 3":"Stellate ganglion",
        "Option 4":"Ciliary ganglion",
        "Option 5":"Gasserian ganglion",
        "Correct Answer":"Stellate ganglion"
    },
    {
        "Question":"58 year old suffering from tumor invading base of cavernous sinus, which nerve is involved?",
        "Option 1":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal",
        "Option 2":"Abducent",
        "Option 3":"Facial",
        "Option 4":"Vestibulocochlear",
        "Option 5":"Glossopharyngeal",
        "Correct Answer":"Abducent"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the most common nerve be injured during submandibular gland excision surgery (submandibular sialadenectomy)?",
        "Option 1":"Marginal mandibular",
        "Option 2":"Lingual",
        "Option 3":"Hypoglossal",
        "Option 4":"Vagus",
        "Option 5":"Accessory",
        "Correct Answer":"Marginal mandibular"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which nerve is affected in submandibular gland excision that leads to asymmetric smile?",
        "Option 1":"Marginal mandibular",
        "Option 2":"Lingual",
        "Option 3":"Hypoglossal",
        "Option 4":"Vagus",
        "Option 5":"Glossopharyngeal",
        "Correct Answer":"Marginal mandibular"
    },
    {
        "Question":"23 year old man has TMJ dislocation after RTA, the patient has severe pain around the TMJ, which nerve is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Auriculotemporal",
        "Option 2":"Infra-alveolar",
        "Option 3":"Great auricular",
        "Option 4":"Great occipital",
        "Option 5":"Lesser occipital",
        "Correct Answer":"Auriculotemporal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"34 year old man has TMJ dislocation after RTA, the patient has severe pain around the TMJ , what type of joint is the TMJ?",
        "Option 1":"Synovial bicondylar hinge joint",
        "Option 2":"Synovial ball and socket joint",
        "Option 3":"Synovial plane joint",
        "Option 4":"Synovial pivot joint",
        "Option 5":"Non synovial joint",
        "Correct Answer":"Synovial bicondylar hinge joint"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Following mastoidectomy surgery, a patient complains of impaired taste sensation, what is the nerve injured?",
        "Option 1":"Chorda tympani",
        "Option 2":"Greater petrosal",
        "Option 3":"Lingual",
        "Option 4":"Glossopharyngeal",
        "Option 5":"Nerve to stapedius",
        "Correct Answer":"Chorda tympani"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the nerve supply to lobule of the ear?",
        "Option 1":"Lesser occipital nerve",
        "Option 2":"Great auricular nerve",
        "Option 3":"Auriculotemporal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Infraorbital nerve",
        "Option 5":"Auricular branch of vagus",
        "Correct Answer":"Great auricular nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After head trauma, 30 year old male suffered from extra dural hemorrhage due to bleeding from middle meningeal artery. Middle meningeal artery passes through which foramina of the skull?",
        "Option 1":"Foramen ovale",
        "Option 2":"Foramen rotundem",
        "Option 3":"Foramen spinosum",
        "Option 4":"Foramen lacerum",
        "Option 5":"Foramen magnum",
        "Correct Answer":"Foramen spinosum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Glossopharyngeal nerve passes in which foramen of the skull?",
        "Option 1":"Hypoglossal",
        "Option 2":"Lacerum",
        "Option 3":"Spinosum",
        "Option 4":"Jugular",
        "Option 5":"Rotundum",
        "Correct Answer":"Jugular"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Foramen of skull in which hypoglossal pass?",
        "Option 1":"foramen ovale",
        "Option 2":"Foramen rotundem",
        "Option 3":"Jugular foramen",
        "Option 4":"Foramen lacerum",
        "Option 5":"Hypoglossal canal",
        "Correct Answer":"Hypoglossal canal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Foramen of skull in which the vagus nerve passes?",
        "Option 1":"foramen ovale",
        "Option 2":"Foramen rotundem",
        "Option 3":"Jugular foramen",
        "Option 4":"Foramen lacerum",
        "Option 5":"Hypoglossal canal",
        "Correct Answer":"Jugular foramen"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which layer of scalp makes scalp easily movable from periosteum?",
        "Option 1":"Skin",
        "Option 2":"Dense connective tissue",
        "Option 3":"Loose areolar tissue",
        "Option 4":"Pericardium",
        "Option 5":"Periosteum",
        "Correct Answer":"Loose areolar tissue"
    },
    {
        "Question":"32 year old has anosmia after head trauma due to skull fracture, which part of skull is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Cribriform plate of ethmoid bone",
        "Option 2":"Christa galli bone",
        "Option 3":"Nasal bones",
        "Option 4":"Maxillary bone",
        "Option 5":"Occipital bone",
        "Correct Answer":"Cribriform plate of ethmoid bone"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 year old presented by epistaxis from the little\u2019s area or kisselbach plexus. What is the most vessels responsible for that epistaxis?",
        "Option 1":"Sphenopalatine",
        "Option 2":"Anterior ethmoidal",
        "Option 3":"Posterior ethmoidal",
        "Option 4":"Greater palatine",
        "Option 5":"Septal of superior labial",
        "Correct Answer":"Sphenopalatine"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 year old presented by epistaxis from superior nasal septum. Which artery is mostly affected?",
        "Option 1":"Nasoethmoidal",
        "Option 2":"Zygomatic",
        "Option 3":"Maxillary",
        "Option 4":"Anterior ethmoidal",
        "Option 5":"Sphenopalatine",
        "Correct Answer":"Anterior ethmoidal"
    },
    {
        "Question":"All are true about cavernous sinus thrombosis except:",
        "Option 1":"Painful swelling of the eye",
        "Option 2":"Ophthalmoplegia",
        "Option 3":"Gradual loss of vision",
        "Option 4":"Inferior pass through valvless facial vein through superior ophthalmic vein to cavernous sinus",
        "Option 5":"Reeah to it by mastoid abscess",
        "Correct Answer":"Reeah to it by mastoid abscess"
    },
    {
        "Question":"60 year old woman with breast carcinoma complains of difficulty chewing her food and is found to have numbness of the lower lip on one side. CT scanning shows a small metastatic lesion affecting the bony skull base on. The same side as the lip numbness. Which foramen is the most likely to involve?",
        "Option 1":"Foramen cecum",
        "Option 2":"Foramen magnum",
        "Option 3":"Foramen ovale",
        "Option 4":"Foramen rotundum",
        "Option 5":"Foramen spinosum",
        "Correct Answer":"Foramen ovale"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Tooth infection , which muscle of the mouth prevents infection to spread from the mouth to neck?",
        "Option 1":"Mylohyoid",
        "Option 2":"Geniohyoid",
        "Option 3":"Platysma",
        "Option 4":"Ant belly of digastric",
        "Option 5":"Buccinator",
        "Correct Answer":"Mylohyoid"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Ludwig angina is infection mainly caused by tooth infection in which space?",
        "Option 1":"Submandibular space",
        "Option 2":"Retropharyngeal space",
        "Option 3":"Parapharyngeal space",
        "Option 4":"Pre vertebral space",
        "Option 5":"Para vertebral space",
        "Correct Answer":"Submandibular space"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Right side of the face is dry and loss of ciliospinal reflex (pupil dilatation in response of painful stimulus of neck), which autonomic ganglia is responsible for that lesion?",
        "Option 1":"Ciliary ganglion",
        "Option 2":"Gasserian ganglion",
        "Option 3":"Satelliate ganglion",
        "Option 4":"Pterygopalatine ganglion",
        "Option 5":"Submandibular ganglion",
        "Correct Answer":"Satelliate ganglion"
    },
    {
        "Question":"40 year old man suffered from injury during maxillofacial surgery that leads to loss of general sensation over the anterior 2\/3 of tongue, what is the nerve affected?",
        "Option 1":"Lingual nerve",
        "Option 2":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Chorda tympani nerve",
        "Option 4":"Hypoglossal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Vagus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Lingual nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 4 year old boy presents to the emergency department with a two day history of headache , vomiting and drowsiness. A CT scan reveals dilatation of both his lateral ventrilcles and his third cerebral ventricle. His fourth ventricle was of normal size. It is suspected that he has obstruction to his CSF flow . at which of the following sites is the obstruction most likely to be?",
        "Option 1":"Cerebral aqueduct (of sylvius)",
        "Option 2":"Infundibular recess",
        "Option 3":"Interventricular foramen",
        "Option 4":"Lateral foramen of fourth ventricle",
        "Option 5":"Median foramen of the fourth ventricle",
        "Correct Answer":"Cerebral aqueduct (of sylvius)"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 60 year old man presents to the emergency department with epistaxis. The source of the bleeding is identified as little\u2019s area and resolves with direct cautery. Which vessel is most likely to be responsible for the bleeding?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior ethmoidal artery",
        "Option 2":"Infraorbital artery",
        "Option 3":"Middle meningeal artery",
        "Option 4":"Sphenopalatine artery",
        "Option 5":"Supratrochlear artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Sphenopalatine artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"20 year old man after blunt trauma to his head resulting in vertex is depressed. Which structure may be damaged?",
        "Option 1":"Superior sagittal sinus",
        "Option 2":"Inferior sagittal sinus",
        "Option 3":"Transverse sinus",
        "Option 4":"Confluence of sinus",
        "Option 5":"Superior sagittal sinus",
        "Correct Answer":null
    },
    {
        "Question":"32 year old is admitted to ER after blunt trauma to his pterion causing extra-dural hemorrhage. What are the four bones forming pterion?",
        "Option 1":"Frontal, temporal, parietal and occipital",
        "Option 2":"Frontal, temporal, parietal and lesser wing of sphenoid",
        "Option 3":"Frontal, temporal, parietal and greater wing of sphenoid",
        "Option 4":"Frontal, temporal , sphenoidal, and occipital",
        "Option 5":"Occipital, temporal, parietal and lesser wing of sphenoidal",
        "Correct Answer":"Frontal, temporal, parietal and greater wing of sphenoid"
    },
    {
        "Question":"32 year old admitted to ER after blunt trauma to his pterion causing extra dural hemorrhage. Which part of temporal bone is involved in pterion?",
        "Option 1":"Petrous",
        "Option 2":"Squamous",
        "Option 3":"Lesser wing of sphenoid",
        "Option 4":"Mastoid",
        "Option 5":"Tympanic",
        "Correct Answer":"Squamous"
    },
    {
        "Question":"29 year old is assaulted and sustained a forceful impact on left temporal area of the head. He develops an extradural hemorrhage, what is the site of the lesion?",
        "Option 1":"Lesser wing of sphenoid",
        "Option 2":"Mastoid process",
        "Option 3":"Occipital bone",
        "Option 4":"Parietal bone",
        "Option 5":"Zygomatic bone",
        "Correct Answer":"Parietal bone"
    },
    {
        "Question":"70 year old man smoker has ulcer on his lateral border of tongue, what is the lymphatic drainage of this part?",
        "Option 1":"Submental lymph node",
        "Option 2":"Bilateral deep cervical lymph node",
        "Option 3":"Ipsilateral submandibular lymph node",
        "Option 4":"Contralateral submandibular lymph node",
        "Option 5":"bilateral submandibular lymph node",
        "Correct Answer":"Ipsilateral submandibular lymph node"
    },
    {
        "Question":"30 years old man with mastoid process infection and pus can cause destruction of which of the following part?",
        "Option 1":"Inner ear",
        "Option 2":"Sigmoid sinus",
        "Option 3":"Occipital sinus",
        "Option 4":"Internal carotid artery",
        "Option 5":"External carotid artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Sigmoid sinus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A young man alleged cut injury from tragus of ear to angle of mouth, what is the structure mostly damaged?",
        "Option 1":"Stenson\u2019s duct",
        "Option 2":"Warton duct",
        "Option 3":"Santorini duct",
        "Option 4":"Wirsung duct",
        "Option 5":"Lacrimal duct",
        "Correct Answer":"Stenson\u2019s duct"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 20 year old patient in the intensive care unit has tracheostomy performed via the second, third and fourth tracheal rings, which intervening structure is most likely to require transection?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior jugular vein",
        "Option 2":"Inferior thyroid veins",
        "Option 3":"Sternomastoid muscle",
        "Option 4":"Thyroid isthmus",
        "Option 5":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Thyroid isthmus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 24 year old man is brought to the emergency room following a RTA. He has obvious airway compromise due to mouth\/ facial hemorrhage which requires a surgical airway. The surface landmarks used to localize the optimal site for a tracheostomy incision are midway between the suprasternal notch and which of the following ?",
        "Option 1":"Cricoid",
        "Option 2":"Hyoid",
        "Option 3":"Mastoid",
        "Option 4":"Laryngeal prominence",
        "Option 5":"Thyroid",
        "Correct Answer":"Hyoid"
    },
    {
        "Question":"3 year old child ingest coin while playing and his parents take him to ER and GP found the coin lodged at which level on xray?",
        "Option 1":"Lodged at level of cricopharyngeal level",
        "Option 2":"Lodged in superior constrictor",
        "Option 3":"Lodged in middle constrictor",
        "Option 4":"Lodged in inferior constrictor",
        "Option 5":"Lodged in the thyropharyneus muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Lodged at level of cricopharyngeal level"
    },
    {
        "Question":"70 year old man presented by neck swelling and when compress it cause regurgitation of food and diagnosed as zenker\u2019s diverticulum in the wall of pharynx. Zenker diverticulum occurs between which muscles?",
        "Option 1":"Between superior and middle constrictors",
        "Option 2":"Between middle and inferior constrictors",
        "Option 3":"Between inferior constrictor and cricopharyngeal muscle",
        "Option 4":"Between false and true vocal cords",
        "Option 5":"Between sternothyroid and thyrohoid muscles",
        "Correct Answer":"Between inferior constrictor and cricopharyngeal muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Emergency mini-tracheostomy site done to patient with airway compromise as he was in street as emergency procedure. What is the site of this mini tracheostomy?",
        "Option 1":"A cricothyroid membrane",
        "Option 2":"3 to 5 tracheal rings",
        "Option 3":"Above thyroid cartilage",
        "Option 4":"Below thyroid cartilage",
        "Option 5":"At hyoid bone",
        "Correct Answer":"A cricothyroid membrane"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following is considered the unique features of axis vertebrae?",
        "Option 1":"Bifid spinous process",
        "Option 2":"Carotid tubercle",
        "Option 3":"No transverse process",
        "Option 4":"No spinous process",
        "Option 5":"Has transverse process",
        "Correct Answer":"Bifid spinous process"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the number of vertebra at which the arrow refers to ?",
        "Option 1":"C1",
        "Option 2":"C2",
        "Option 3":"C3",
        "Option 4":"C4",
        "Option 5":"C5",
        "Correct Answer":"C2"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male old patient has vertebral mass but cannot cause respiratory compromise. What is the level of vertebral mass?",
        "Option 1":"Mandible",
        "Option 2":"Cricoid",
        "Option 3":"Thyroid",
        "Option 4":"Hyoid",
        "Option 5":"Odontoid",
        "Correct Answer":"Cricoid"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 37 year old man presents with severe headache, photophobia and neck stifness. Kernig\u2019s sign is positive and a midline lumber puncture is performed immediately to determine if a CSF pathogen is involved. In performing this procedure, which is the first structure to be pierced by the lumbar puncture?",
        "Option 1":"Arachinoid matter",
        "Option 2":"Dura matter",
        "Option 3":"Interspinous ligament",
        "Option 4":"Posterior longitudinal ligament",
        "Option 5":"Anterior longitudinal ligament",
        "Correct Answer":"Interspinous ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35 year old man presents with a three week history of low back pain and 3 day history of pain and weakness in his left leg. Physical examination demonstrated numbness over the posterior aspect of the left calf extending to the lateral aspect of the foot. Left ankle reflex is absent. A MRI shows compression of the left S1 nerve root. What is the most likely responsible structure?",
        "Option 1":"Annulus fibrosus",
        "Option 2":"Anterior longitudinal ligament",
        "Option 3":"Posterior longitudinal ligament",
        "Option 4":"Nucleus pulposus",
        "Option 5":"Vertebral end plate",
        "Correct Answer":"Nucleus pulposus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Lumber puncture done in which space?",
        "Option 1":"Subarachnoid",
        "Option 2":"Subdural",
        "Option 3":"Epidural",
        "Option 4":"Sub pia matter",
        "Option 5":"Sub glial",
        "Correct Answer":"Subarachnoid"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 21 year old man comes into emergency department with severe headache and neck stiffness of recent onset. You suspect acute meningitis and decide immediately to treat with antibiotics and perform a lumbar puncture. After your third attempt to obtain CSF you notice that the fluid obtained is stained red. However, during collection of CSF into three continers it is noted that the final bottle is now cleared of any blood. Which anatomical structure is most likely to be responsible for this bleeding?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior spinal artery",
        "Option 2":"Epidural artery",
        "Option 3":"Subarachnoid vein",
        "Option 4":"Veins within the erector spinae muscle",
        "Option 5":"Vertebral venous plexus",
        "Correct Answer":"Vertebral venous plexus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 37 year old man presents with severe headache, photophobia and neck stifness. Kernig\u2019s sign is positive and a midline lumber puncture is performed immediately to determine if a CSF pathogen is involved. In performing this procedure, which is the first structure to be pierced by the lumbar puncture?",
        "Option 1":"Arachnoid mater",
        "Option 2":"Dura mater",
        "Option 3":"Ligamentum flavum",
        "Option 4":"Posterior longitudinal ligament",
        "Option 5":"Anterior longitudinal ligament",
        "Correct Answer":"Ligamentum flavum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which one of the following is true?",
        "Option 1":"Epidural should below L4 to prevent injury of spinal cord",
        "Option 2":"Dura meninges end at S2 in adults",
        "Option 3":"Conus medullaris end between L2-L3",
        "Option 4":"Lumbar puncture should be L1-L2",
        "Option 5":"lumbar puncture last structure is dura mater",
        "Correct Answer":"Dura meninges end at S2 in adults"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 37 year old man presents with severe headache, photophobia and neck stifness. Kernig\u2019s sign is positive and a midline lumber puncture is performed immediately to determine if a CSF pathogen is involved. In performing this procedure, which is the last structure to be pierced by the lumbar puncture?",
        "Option 1":"Supraspinous ligament",
        "Option 2":"Interspinous ligament",
        "Option 3":"Ligamentum flavum",
        "Option 4":"Arachinoid",
        "Option 5":"Dura",
        "Correct Answer":"Arachinoid"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 66 year old woman with known tumor of her spine has started to retain urine and is experiencing decreased anal and rectal tone. The tumor is pressing directly on the conus medullaris. At which of the following vertebral levels is the tumor most likely to be located?",
        "Option 1":"T9-10",
        "Option 2":"T11-12",
        "Option 3":"L1-2",
        "Option 4":"L3-4",
        "Option 5":"L5-S1",
        "Correct Answer":"L1-2"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 37 year old man presents with severe headache, photophobia and neck stifness. Kernig\u2019s sign is positive and a midline lumber puncture is performed immediately to determine if a CSF pathogen is involved. In performing this procedure, at which level we do this procedure?",
        "Option 1":"At iliac crest",
        "Option 2":"At anterior iliac spine",
        "Option 3":"Transpyloric plane",
        "Option 4":"Subcostal plane",
        "Option 5":"Umbilicus plane",
        "Correct Answer":"At iliac crest"
    },
    {
        "Question":"In adults, what is correct statement regarding lumbar puncture?",
        "Option 1":"Preferred at the level of iliac crest as the cord ends above this level",
        "Option 2":"At the level of trans tubercular plane as the sacral canal is widest here",
        "Option 3":"At the level of posterior inferior iliac spine",
        "Option 4":"At t12 level as the spinal canal is narrowest at this level",
        "Option 5":"At the level of anterior superior iliac spine",
        "Correct Answer":"Preferred at the level of iliac crest as the cord ends above this level"
    },
    {
        "Question":"In lumber puncture, what is the structure of the following is not pierced?",
        "Option 1":"Supraspinous ligament",
        "Option 2":"Interspinous ligament",
        "Option 3":"Ligamentum flavum",
        "Option 4":"Arachinoid",
        "Option 5":"Posterior longitudinal ligament",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior longitudinal ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the level of conus medullaris termination in children?",
        "Option 1":"L1",
        "Option 2":"L2",
        "Option 3":"L3",
        "Option 4":"L5",
        "Option 5":"S2",
        "Correct Answer":"L3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the level of lumbar cistern where CSF is ended?",
        "Option 1":"L1",
        "Option 2":"L3",
        "Option 3":"S1",
        "Option 4":"S2",
        "Option 5":"S3",
        "Correct Answer":"S2"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following can be used as  a surface landmark for external jugular vein?",
        "Option 1":"Lobule of the ear to the sternoclavicular joint",
        "Option 2":"Mastoid to the sternoclavicular joint",
        "Option 3":"Styloid process to the sternoclavicular joint",
        "Option 4":"Anterior border of sternocleomastoid",
        "Option 5":"The angle of mandible to the middle 3rd of the clavicle",
        "Correct Answer":"The angle of mandible to the middle 3rd of the clavicle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following can be used as surface anatomy of internal carotid artery?",
        "Option 1":"From anterior sternomastoid border at upper thyroid cartilage up to posterior border of neck of mandible",
        "Option 2":"From lobule of the ear to sternoclavicular joint",
        "Option 3":"From styloid process to sternoclavicular joint",
        "Option 4":"From the middle third of the clavicle to angle of mandible",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"From anterior sternomastoid border at upper thyroid cartilage up to posterior border of neck of mandible"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During arch aortography, the vertebral artery would be seen arise directly from which of the following artery?",
        "Option 1":"Arch of aorta",
        "Option 2":"Axillary 2nd part",
        "Option 3":"Axillary 1st part",
        "Option 4":"Subclavian artery 3rd part",
        "Option 5":"Subclavian artery 1st part",
        "Correct Answer":"Subclavian artery 1st part"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 year old man has a history of transient ischemic attacks. He is due to undergo carotid endarterectomy, which one of the following is true of internal carotid artery?",
        "Option 1":"Begins at level of the sixth cervical vertebra",
        "Option 2":"Divides into anterior, middle and posterior cerebral arteries",
        "Option 3":"Gives off ophthalmic artery",
        "Option 4":"Is accompanied within the skull by preganglionic sympathetic nerves",
        "Option 5":"Passes through the foramen ovale",
        "Correct Answer":"Gives off ophthalmic artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"With regards to the jugular vein, which of the following statements is untrue?",
        "Option 1":"It lies within the carotid sheath",
        "Option 2":"It is the continuation of sigmoid sinus",
        "Option 3":"The terminal part of the thoracic duct crosses anterior to it to insert into the right subclavian vein",
        "Option 4":"The hypoglossal nerve is closely related to it as it passes near the atlas",
        "Option 5":"The vagus nerve is closely related to it within the carotid sheath",
        "Correct Answer":"The terminal part of the thoracic duct crosses anterior to it to insert into the right subclavian vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 26 year old man is having a stereotactic frame fitted to his skull prior to radiosurgery on a cerebral AV malformation, four pins secure the frame tightly through the scalp to the outer table of the skull, two anteriorly two posteriorly. On insertion of one of the posterior pins, arterial hemorrhage is encountered, which artery is most likely to have been punctured?",
        "Option 1":"Ascending pharyngeal",
        "Option 2":"Middle meningeal",
        "Option 3":"Occipital",
        "Option 4":"Posterior cerebral",
        "Option 5":"Posterior communicating",
        "Correct Answer":"Occipital"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65 year old man with known ischemic heart disease and atrial fibrillation presents with a paralysis of his right lower limb. Which arterial territory is most likely to be involved?",
        "Option 1":"Left anterior cerebral",
        "Option 2":"Left middle cerebral",
        "Option 3":"Right anterior cerebral",
        "Option 4":"Right middle cerebral",
        "Option 5":"Right posterior cerebral",
        "Correct Answer":"Left anterior cerebral"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 60 year old patient developing sudden urinary retention and bilateral lower limb paresis. Which artery is affected in which of the following scenarios?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior spinal artery",
        "Option 2":"Artery of adamchweick",
        "Option 3":"Lumbar artery",
        "Option 4":"Posterior spinal artery",
        "Option 5":"Verterbral artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Artery of adamchweick"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50 year old man presented by cerebral stroke and physician told you that he has broca\u2019s aphasia and spastic hemiplegia, which artery is mostly affected?",
        "Option 1":"Left anterior cerebral artery",
        "Option 2":"Left middle cerebral artery",
        "Option 3":"Right anterior cerebral artery",
        "Option 4":"Left anterior cerebral artery",
        "Option 5":"Right posterior cerebral artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Left middle cerebral artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"55 year old man came to emergency room with his family due to sudden verbal aphasia. Which arterial territory is mainly affected?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior cerebral artery",
        "Option 2":"Posterior cerebral artery",
        "Option 3":"Middle cerebral artery",
        "Option 4":"Anterior inferior cerebellar artery",
        "Option 5":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Middle cerebral artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"45 year old patient presented after brain stroke and physician told you that he suffered from nystagmus and ataxia. Which artery is mostly affected?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior cerebral artery",
        "Option 2":"Middle meningeal",
        "Option 3":"Middle cerebral artery",
        "Option 4":"Ophthalmic artery",
        "Option 5":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"2 year old child presented with Arnold chiari syndrome due to cerebellar tonsil herniation through foramen magnum and associated with syrengiomeylia syndrome. Which of the following tract is affected?",
        "Option 1":"Dorsal column",
        "Option 2":"Spinothalamic tract",
        "Option 3":"Corticospinal tract",
        "Option 4":"Extrapyramidal tract",
        "Option 5":"Cerebrospinal tract",
        "Correct Answer":"Spinothalamic tract"
    },
    {
        "Question":"20 year old man presenting after head injury with decrease GCS from 13 to 8 with lucid interval in between. What is the artery mostly damaged?",
        "Option 1":"Middle meningeal artery",
        "Option 2":"Sphenopalatine artery",
        "Option 3":"Anterior cerebral artery",
        "Option 4":"Middle cerebral artery",
        "Option 5":"posterior cerebral artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Middle meningeal artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"vertebral artery passes through all the following foramina except?",
        "Option 1":"C3 transverse foramina",
        "Option 2":"C4 transverse foramina",
        "Option 3":"C5 transverse foramina",
        "Option 4":"C6 transverse foramina",
        "Option 5":"C7 transverse foramina",
        "Correct Answer":"C7 transverse foramina"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following is the 1st branch of internal carotid as soon as it leaves the cavernous sinus?",
        "Option 1":"Ophthalmic artery",
        "Option 2":"ACA",
        "Option 3":"MCA",
        "Option 4":"Posterior communicating",
        "Option 5":"Anterior choroid artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Ophthalmic artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"35 year old patient with fracture base of skull and suspected having CSF rhinorrhea. What is the best Test for CSF leak?",
        "Option 1":"Albumin",
        "Option 2":"Calcitonin",
        "Option 3":"Ferritin",
        "Option 4":"B2 transferrin",
        "Option 5":"Serotonin",
        "Correct Answer":"B2 transferrin"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Disc prolapse occurs due to deficient of which structure of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Nucleus pulposus",
        "Option 2":"Posterior longitudinal ligament",
        "Option 3":"Annulus fibrosus",
        "Option 4":"Ligamentum flavum",
        "Option 5":"Annulus fibrosus",
        "Correct Answer":null
    },
    {
        "Question":"Vertebral artery true is enters the foramen transversum at which level?",
        "Option 1":"C3",
        "Option 2":"C4",
        "Option 3":"C5",
        "Option 4":"C6",
        "Option 5":"C7",
        "Correct Answer":"C6"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which part of the brain will be supplied by the vertebral artery?",
        "Option 1":"Frontal lobe",
        "Option 2":"Parietal lobe",
        "Option 3":"Occipital lobe",
        "Option 4":"Temporal lobe",
        "Option 5":"Prefrontal cortex",
        "Correct Answer":"Occipital lobe"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the problem that may develop after basilar artery occlusion?",
        "Option 1":"Visual problems",
        "Option 2":"Auditory problems",
        "Option 3":"memory problems",
        "Option 4":"motor problems",
        "Option 5":"sensory problems",
        "Correct Answer":"Visual problems"
    },
    {
        "Question":"a 30 year old male is admitted to hospital following RTA in which there is stable fracture pelvis and a head injury. Which of the following is most likely to be elevated after the first 24 hours?",
        "Option 1":"Albumin",
        "Option 2":"Amylase",
        "Option 3":"Troponin T",
        "Option 4":"RBC",
        "Option 5":"CRP",
        "Correct Answer":"Troponin T"
    },
    {
        "Question":"When taking a sample match the procedure to the last structure that you go through?",
        "Option 1":"Pleural tab\/ visceral pleura",
        "Option 2":"Abdominocentesis\/ visceral peritoneum",
        "Option 3":"Lumber puncture\/ arachnoid matter",
        "Option 4":"Pericardiocentesis\/ myocardium",
        "Option 5":"Renal biopsy\/ parietal peritoneum",
        "Correct Answer":"Lumber puncture\/ arachnoid matter"
    },
    {
        "Question":"50 year old patient has malignant melanoma and cervical lymph nodes enlargement. On removal of level V neck dissection for malignant melanoma in the posterior triangle supraclavicular lymph nodes. Which nerve is most likely to damaged and cause this symptom?",
        "Option 1":"Dysarthria",
        "Option 2":"Loss of high pitched voice",
        "Option 3":"Hoarsness of voice",
        "Option 4":"Dyspnea",
        "Option 5":"Weak shoulder",
        "Correct Answer":"Weak shoulder"
    },
    {
        "Question":"20 year old man presenting after head injury with decrease GCS from 13 to 8 with lucid interval in between. What is the artery mostly damaged is branch from?",
        "Option 1":"Sphenopalatine",
        "Option 2":"Maxillary",
        "Option 3":"Superficial temporal",
        "Option 4":"Facial",
        "Option 5":"Posterior cerebral",
        "Correct Answer":"Maxillary"
    },
    {
        "Question":"15 year old child suffered from uneven smile after upper deep cervical lymph node biopsy. Where is the nerve affected?",
        "Option 1":"Buccal",
        "Option 2":"Mental",
        "Option 3":"Inferior alveolar",
        "Option 4":"Cervical branch of facial",
        "Option 5":"Marginal mandibular branch",
        "Correct Answer":"Marginal mandibular branch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Injury to parietal lobe will result in lesion at which part of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Optic nerve",
        "Option 2":"Optic radiation",
        "Option 3":"Optic chiasma",
        "Option 4":"Lateral geniculate body",
        "Option 5":"Optic tract",
        "Correct Answer":"Optic radiation"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient has pain on ipsilateral side of face and ophthalmoplegia is seen. Where are the nerves responsible passing through?",
        "Option 1":"Foramen ovale",
        "Option 2":"Foramen rotundum",
        "Option 3":"Superior orbital fissure",
        "Option 4":"Foramen magnum",
        "Option 5":"Foramen spinosum",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior orbital fissure"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the structures listed below is a content of the carotid sheath along with internal jugular vein and carotid arteries?",
        "Option 1":"External jugular vein",
        "Option 2":"Phrenic nerve",
        "Option 3":"Hypoglossal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Vagus nerve",
        "Option 5":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Vagus nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the laryngeal muscle causing abduction of the vocal cord?",
        "Option 1":"Lateral cricoarytenoid muscle",
        "Option 2":"Posterior cricoarytenoid muscle",
        "Option 3":"Cricothyroid muscle",
        "Option 4":"Cricothyroid muscle",
        "Option 5":"Thyrohyoid muscle",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior cricoarytenoid muscle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following sinus drains into superior meatus of the nasal cavity?",
        "Option 1":"Anterior ethmoid sinus",
        "Option 2":"Posterior ethmoid sinus",
        "Option 3":"Frontal sinus",
        "Option 4":"Maxillary sinus",
        "Option 5":"Nasolacrimal duct",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior ethmoid sinus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 21 year old man undergoes an uncomplicated tonsillectomy for recurrent attacks of tonsillitis. Post operatively he complains of otalgia. The nerve affected originates from which arch?",
        "Option 1":"1",
        "Option 2":"2",
        "Option 3":"3",
        "Option 4":"4",
        "Option 5":"6",
        "Correct Answer":"3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the level of bifurcation of common carotid arteries?",
        "Option 1":"C2",
        "Option 2":"C3",
        "Option 3":"C4",
        "Option 4":"C5",
        "Option 5":"C6",
        "Correct Answer":"C3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"35 year old lady presents with sensorineural hearing loss an MRI scan reveals a tumor of the cerebello-pontine angle. Tumor arising from which nerve?",
        "Option 1":"Vestibulocochlear nerve",
        "Option 2":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Trigeminal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Vagus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Vestibulocochlear nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the nerve origin of acoustic neuroma?",
        "Option 1":"Vestibulocochlear nerve",
        "Option 2":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Trigeminal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Vagus nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Vestibulocochlear nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following muscle is not from facial muscle?",
        "Option 1":"Temporalis",
        "Option 2":"Buccinator",
        "Option 3":"Mentalis",
        "Option 4":"Platysma",
        "Option 5":"Orbicularis oris",
        "Correct Answer":"Temporalis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of muscle is not involved in TMJ movement?",
        "Option 1":"Buccinator",
        "Option 2":"Medial pterygoid",
        "Option 3":"Lateral pterygoid",
        "Option 4":"Masseter",
        "Option 5":"Temporalis",
        "Correct Answer":"Buccinator"
    },
    {
        "Question":"24 year old patient develops numbness of gum, chin and lower lip after tooth extraction. Which nerve traversing through the body of mandible is responsible for that?",
        "Option 1":"Lingual nerve",
        "Option 2":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Mental nerve",
        "Option 4":"Inferior alveolar nerve",
        "Option 5":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior alveolar nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Temporal bone fracture after high velocity accident, patient has otorrhea. Damage to which structure causes CSF to leak externally?",
        "Option 1":"Internal auditory meatus",
        "Option 2":"Tympanic membrane",
        "Option 3":"Tegmen tympani",
        "Option 4":"Secondary tympanic membrane",
        "Option 5":"Eustachian tube",
        "Correct Answer":"Tegmen tympani"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 4 year old boy presents to the emergency department with a two day history of headache , vomiting and drowsiness. A CT scan revealed dilatation of both his lateral ventricles. His third and fourth ventricles were of normal size. It is suspected that he has an obstruction to his CSF flow. At which level is the obstruction likely to be?",
        "Option 1":"Cerebral aqueduct (of sylvius)",
        "Option 2":"Infundibular recess",
        "Option 3":"Interventricular foramen (of Monroe)",
        "Option 4":"Lateral foramen of fourth ventricle",
        "Option 5":"Median foramen of the fourth ventricle",
        "Correct Answer":"Interventricular foramen (of Monroe)"
    },
    {
        "Question":"45 year old female patient after parotid surgery has assymtrical, dry face, absent forehead wrinkles. What is the nerve injured?",
        "Option 1":"Temporal branch of facial",
        "Option 2":"Zygomatic branch of facial",
        "Option 3":"Buccal branch of facial",
        "Option 4":"Cervical branch of facial",
        "Option 5":"Zygomaticotemporal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Temporal branch of facial"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During the submandibular gland surgery. What is the artery at risk?",
        "Option 1":"Lingual artery",
        "Option 2":"Facial artery",
        "Option 3":"External carotid artery",
        "Option 4":"Internal carotid artery",
        "Option 5":"Superficial temporal artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Facial artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 56 year old man presents with headache and vomiting with deterioration over the last two weeks. On examination he develops a sudden homonymous hemianopia. Which part of the visual system to be affected?",
        "Option 1":"Lens",
        "Option 2":"Optic chiasm",
        "Option 3":"Optic radiation",
        "Option 4":"Optic tract",
        "Option 5":"Optic nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Optic tract"
    },
    {
        "Question":"39 year old man after trauma to face. After examination, the cheek is flat and depressed. He developed ecchymosis around eye and complains of some diplopia and numbness over the cheek. What is the bone affected",
        "Option 1":"Maxillary",
        "Option 2":"Zygomatic",
        "Option 3":"Frontal",
        "Option 4":"Nasal",
        "Option 5":"Sphenoid",
        "Correct Answer":"Zygomatic"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 20 year old man presented with pain when brushing lower teeth & jaw. What is the nerve affected and from which foramen?",
        "Option 1":"Hypoglossal nerve and hypoglossal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Accessory nerve and jugular foramen",
        "Option 3":"Vagus nerve and jugular foramen",
        "Option 4":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal and foramen ovale",
        "Option 5":"Maxillary branch of trigeminal and foramen rotundum",
        "Correct Answer":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal and foramen ovale"
    },
    {
        "Question":"There is cavernous sinus pathology. Which of the following is not affected?",
        "Option 1":"Movement of the eye",
        "Option 2":"Sensation to lower lip",
        "Option 3":"Sensation to cheek",
        "Option 4":"Sensation to cornea",
        "Option 5":"sensation to nose",
        "Correct Answer":"Sensation to lower lip"
    },
    {
        "Question":"patient has tingling on ipsilateral side of front of head and ophthalmoplegia is seen. Where are the nerves responsible passing through?",
        "Option 1":"Superior orbital fissure",
        "Option 2":"Foramen ovale",
        "Option 3":"Foramen rotundum",
        "Option 4":"Foramen magnum",
        "Option 5":"Foramen spinousm",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior orbital fissure"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Gag reflex is when you touch palate: there is contraction of muscles of palate and uvula. Which arch made cranial nerve carry afferent fibers from gag reflex?",
        "Option 1":"1st",
        "Option 2":"2nd",
        "Option 3":"3rd",
        "Option 4":"4th",
        "Option 5":"6th",
        "Correct Answer":"3rd"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient presented by loss of sensation of lower lip and he can\u2019t close his mouth properly. What is the nerve affected?",
        "Option 1":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 2":"Trigeminal nerve",
        "Option 3":"Accessory nerve",
        "Option 4":"Vagus nerve",
        "Option 5":"Inferior alveolar nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Trigeminal nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Young female after piercing tip of her tongue. She has neck lymph node enlargement. What is mainly first lymph node affected?",
        "Option 1":"Submandibular lymph nodes",
        "Option 2":"Lower deep cervical lymph nodes",
        "Option 3":"Upper deep cervical lymph nodes",
        "Option 4":"Pre auricular lymph nodes",
        "Option 5":"Submental lymph nodes",
        "Correct Answer":"Submental lymph nodes"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During tracheostomy, the surgeon divides strap muscles from its lower part, what it is the type of nerve supply of strap muscles?",
        "Option 1":"Purely motor",
        "Option 2":"Purely sensory",
        "Option 3":"Mixed",
        "Option 4":"Sympathetic",
        "Option 5":"Parasympathetic",
        "Correct Answer":"Purely motor"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Chorda tympani exit from skull through which foramen?",
        "Option 1":"Internal carotid meatus",
        "Option 2":"External acoustic meatus",
        "Option 3":"Pterygotympanic fissure",
        "Option 4":"Stylomastoid foramen",
        "Option 5":"Jugular foramen",
        "Correct Answer":"Pterygotympanic fissure"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Trauma to face nurse notices pupil is wide and abducted depressed eye. What is the cause of depression in abduction?",
        "Option 1":"Optic nerve",
        "Option 2":"Oculomotor nerve",
        "Option 3":"Trochlear nerve",
        "Option 4":"Abducent nerve",
        "Option 5":"Facial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Trochlear nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"56 years old needs central line for total parentral nutrition in his neck. What is the landmark for central line?",
        "Option 1":"Lobule of the ear to the sternoclavicular joint",
        "Option 2":"Mastoid to the sternoclavicular joint",
        "Option 3":"Styloid process to the sternoclavicular joint",
        "Option 4":"Anterior border of sternocleidomastoid",
        "Option 5":"The angle of jaw to the middle 3rd of the clavicle",
        "Correct Answer":"Lobule of the ear to the sternoclavicular joint"
    },
    {
        "Question":"45 years old man suffered from right sided mass at the back of mandible body. Where its duct open?",
        "Option 1":"Opposite 2nd upper molar tooth",
        "Option 2":"Opposite lower 2nd molar",
        "Option 3":"Floor of the mouth",
        "Option 4":"Palate",
        "Option 5":"Sublingual",
        "Correct Answer":"Opposite 2nd upper molar tooth"
    },
    {
        "Question":"There is an injury at the angle of jaw and there is nerve damage. What is the sensory nerve supply to angle of jaw?",
        "Option 1":"Maxillary branch of trigeminal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal nerve",
        "Option 3":"C3-4 transverse cervical nerve",
        "Option 4":"C2 \u2013 3 great auricular nerve",
        "Option 5":"Buccal branch of facial nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"C2 \u2013 3 great auricular nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the venous site present at the bottom of the falx cerebri?",
        "Option 1":"Superior sagittal sinus",
        "Option 2":"Inferior sagittal sinus",
        "Option 3":"Transverse sinus",
        "Option 4":"Occipital sinus",
        "Option 5":"Sigmoid sinus",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior sagittal sinus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male patient has symptoms of increased intracranial tension, hemiplegia and facial weakness. After investigation, there is thrombosis in transverse sinus. What is bone of skull related to transverse sinus?",
        "Option 1":"Lateral occipital bone",
        "Option 2":"Temporal bone",
        "Option 3":"Coronal suture",
        "Option 4":"Lambdoid suture",
        "Option 5":"Occipital bone",
        "Correct Answer":"Occipital bone"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Blood supply of parathyroid gland",
        "Option 1":"Superior thyroid artery",
        "Option 2":"Middle thyroid artery",
        "Option 3":"Inferior thyroid artery",
        "Option 4":"External carotid artery",
        "Option 5":"Facial artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior thyroid artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During injury of nerve passing in foramen ovale, which muscle will not be affected in closing the mouth",
        "Option 1":"Temporalis",
        "Option 2":"Masseter",
        "Option 3":"Buccinator",
        "Option 4":"Medial pterygoid",
        "Option 5":"Lateral pterygoid",
        "Correct Answer":"Buccinator"
    },
    {
        "Question":"56 year old needs central line for total parentral nutrition in his neck. From which point inserting central line to the medial end of clavicle?",
        "Option 1":"Lobule of the ear",
        "Option 2":"Mastoid",
        "Option 3":"Styloid",
        "Option 4":"Stylomastoid foramen",
        "Option 5":"The angle of jaw",
        "Correct Answer":"Lobule of the ear"
    },
    {
        "Question":"During operation in the neck, there is injury to spinal accessory nerve causing weakness of left shoulder and can\u2019t elevate his arm, what is the other movement affected?",
        "Option 1":"Rotation of the head to right shoulder",
        "Option 2":"Rotation of the head to the left shoulder",
        "Option 3":"Flexion of neck to right shoulder",
        "Option 4":"Flexion of neck to left shoulder",
        "Option 5":"Extension of the neck",
        "Correct Answer":"Rotation of the head to right shoulder"
    }
]